ABDURAHMAN **M**UZEYN

Minneapolis, MN 55311 | Phone: 612-306-9521 | Email: etabdi@yahoo.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdu-muzeyn | GitHub: https://github.com/etabdi

Portfolio: https://abdu-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Passionate web developer with strong engineering background. Strong attention to detail, versatility, and enthusiasm while working in a fast paced work environment. My strong working knowledge of development techniques combined with my experience in collaborative, deadline-driven work environment makes me a great addition to develop high end full-stack web apps. Ready-set to take part in innovative projects such as assisting in preparing development project plans.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Java, handlebars

Database: MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Access, **Other:** Heroku, Git, Bash, Microsoft Office Suite

PROJECTS

Food mood: - Live Demo | Github Repo

2019

A Full-stack app that help user to plan vacations in a group or individual

- FoodMood is a restaurant finder app that allows the user to input their location as well as a specific type of cuisine they are in the mood for. Once it has this information, it will show results in an area.
- The application will utilize APIs, which will retrieve information both about the restaurants and about the routes to the restaurants. This information will ultimately help the user decide which restaurant to go to for the specific type of cuisine they are in the mood for.

DayDream: - Live Demo | Github Repo

2019

FoodMood is a restaurant finder app

- Designed an app that allows customers to plane vacation. he user to input their location as well as a specific type of cuisine they are in the mood for. Once it has this information, it will show them results in their area.
- Tools used: Node.JS, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Express-cryptert and Handlebars
- The application utilize travel gadgets HTML and JavaScript applications which gives additional resources to search restaurants, plane ticket and hotel.

ModernCover: - <u>Live Demo</u> | <u>Github Repo</u>

2019

A MERON stack e-commerce app

- An e-commerce plat Fully functional e-commerce website prototype built using React .
- Tools used: React, Express, MangoDB, Node js, Express-cryptert and Jade js

EXPERIENCE

Tolomatic Manufacturing Engineering Tech

Hamel, MN 2015 – Present

Support Electric Linear Motion Product assembly by providing technical support regarding assembling, testing and troubleshooting of motion products (electric actuators, motors and drives).

Midwest Hospitality Maintenance Engineering

Minneapolis, MN 2014 - 2018

• Adjusts and repairs electronic problems on hotel equipment.

- Completes assigned work orders for general repair within assigned time frame in order to achieve the utmost operational efficiency of the hotel and its equipment.
- Immediately and courteously responds to guests needs in order to repair and/or resolve room maintenance requests and problems as they arise.

AH Engineering Building Engineer

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia 2006 – 2013

- Develop plan views, cross section, construction details, etc. for the buildings to be constructed.
- Employ structural analysis to determine loads on structural members.
- •
- Develop preliminary drawings for buildings in the initial state of quoting.
- Develop estimates for various client buildings; i.e. quantity take-off of materials and applicable material costing.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University of Minnesota – Minneapolis/St.paul, MN

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React, Java